{"tossups": [{"question": "A poem with this title invokes the image of a \"starved and phthisic negress. . . whoseeks...the palms of Africa\". This figure is the second in the title of a poem thatasks of \"terrified vague fingers\" pushing back the \"glory from her loosening thighs\".In a short story, one of these (+) creatures is advised to \"learn to purr as quicklyas possible\" before venturing back out into the world, while another poem says that \"Their hearts have not grown old\" in discussing the \"bell-beat\" they create in the poet's (*) \"nineteenth autumn\". A poem about one of these animals escaping its cage was written by Charles Baudelaire for Les Fleurs du Mal. For ten points, name this type of animal \"nine-and-fifty\" of which flew wild at Coole in a Yeats poem and into which Hans Christian Andersen's ugly duckling turned.", "answer": "swan", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In one story by this man, a character quotes Herbert Spencer's definition of lifeand concludes that \"consciousness is the creature of rhythm\". The protagonist ofanother story by this author remembers that all famous marksmen had gray eyes aftera (+) sentinel's shot missed him. One of his characters uses the example of the rootsof a eucalyptus tree looking for water to prove that plants think, and the narrator of that work is saved from a burning house by the metal worker Haley after the death of the title character. This man, who wrote of a (*) chess-playing robot in Moxon's Master, wrote of a protagonist being told of a large amount of driftwood against a wooden pier that would \"burn like tow\" by a Federal scout before dreaming of his escape. For ten points, name this man who wrote about the hanging of Peyton Fahrquhar in An Occurrence at Owl Creek Bridge.", "answer": "Ambrose Bierce", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This poet posits \"Perhaps the roses really want to grow\" in a villanelle thatconcludes \"Will Time say nothing but I told you so?/ If I could tell you I wouldlet you know\". In another poem, this writer hears a man singing of his eternal loveinterrupted by (+) clocks that chime \"O let not Time deceive you/ You cannotconquer Time.\" In a third work, he notes \"That the dreadful martyrdom must run its course\". This author of (*) As I Walked Out One Evening gives the commands \"Prevent the dog from barking with a juicy bone\" and \"Pack up the stars and dismantle the sun\" in a work sometimes titled Stop All The Clocks, and describes Brueghel's Fall of Icarus in a work which opens \"About suffering they were never wrong/ The Old Masters\". For ten points, name this poet of Funeral Blues and Mus`ee des Beaux Arts.", "answer": "Wystan Hugh Auden                                                                                                                                                                                              ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One character in this novel planted \"circus trees\" but moved away before he atetheir fruit. Another character in this novel noted that pre-Christian Swedes believedthat linden trees resolved magic. Another character briefly abducted his friend'swife Angelique after a (+) jumping contest, and he gave a handful of turquoise fromMexico City to Marie before kissing her during a blackout. The protagonist consults Crazy Ivar about pig rearing at the farm she works with her brothers, (*) Lou and Oscar. That protagonist is visited by an engraver moving from St. Louis to Alaska to speculate named Carl Linstrum. Marie and Emil are shot underneath a mulberry tree by Frank Shabata. For ten points, name this novel about Alexandra Bergson's Nebraska homestead written by Willa Cather.", "answer": "O Pioneers!", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In this work, a cautionary tale is told of Jeanie, who \"Fell sick and died/ in hergay prime.\" One character is incensed when, waiting by a brook, she cannot hear thecalls her sister can. Characters in this work are referred to by the names \"cat-faced\",\"rat-faced\", \"snail-paced\", and \"parrot-voiced\". One character, having no (+) money,pays for her food and wine with a \"golden curl\" of her hair, while another has a penny returned to her after she is not allowed to take food home, the (*) merchants claiming \"Half their dew would dry/ Half their flavour would pass by\". This poem observes that \"One may lead a horse to water,/ Twenty cannot make him drink.\" The title characters repeatedly tempt \"Come buy our orchard fruits\". For ten points, name this poem about Laura and Lizzie written by Christina Rossetti.", "answer": "Goblin Market", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This author wrote a story in which a translator loses a black sweater while tryingon clothes while on vacation. That story, The Exchange, was originally written inItalian. In a novel, this author wrote of a pair of brothers who get caught sneaking intothe (+) Tollyclub golf course. One of those brothers studies in Rhode Island while theother is killed as part of the Naxalite movement. This creator of Subhash and Udayan wrote another novel in which the protagonist divorces (*) Moushumi. That protagonist, as an architecture student at Yale, legally changed his name to Nikhil. That character's birth name was inspired by his father's survival of a train wreck while reading a book of Russian literature. For ten points, name this author of The Lowland who wrote of Ashoke and Gogol Ganguli in The Namesake.", "answer": "Jhumpa Lahiri", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This character takes her first confession after following Laura Danker to church.After this character moves from New York to Farbrook, New Jersey, she is told notto wear socks by Nancy. While at the Steak Place, she learns that Nancy's postcardclaiming (+) \"I GOT IT!!!\" was a lie. This student of first-year teacher Miles Benedict,Jr. has her feet stepped on at a square dance by Philip Leroy. She makes fun of the representative of the (*) Private Lady Company and opts for Teenage Softies. This member of the Pre-Teen Sensations prays \"Don't you think it's time for me to start growing?\". For ten points, name this character who gets her period in a novel by Judy Blume and asks \"Are you there God? It's me\".", "answer": "Margaret Simon", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One character in this novel repeatedly refers to her husband as her \"cara sposo\";that character had recently moved from Maple Grove, the estate of her brother,Mr. Suckling. Another character in this novel burns a pencil and some court plasterleftover from a finger cut that she had kept in her (+) Most Precious Treasures box.The title character is surprised when she learns of a certain man's affections because he had requested a picture she drew of her best friend; that revelation took place in a (*) carriage home on Christmas Eve from the Weston's home. One lady is left without a dancing partner at a ball at the Crown Inn until Mr. Knightley steps in. A proposal from Mr. Martin is initially rejected and later accepted by Harriet Smith. For ten points, name this novel about Miss Woodhouse, the title matchmaker, by Jane Austen.", "answer": "Emma", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A character in one of these locations tells of being fired for graphing the alcoholconsumption of his coworkers and is confronted by the devil with riddles, none ofwhose answers is Petushki, in a work of Venedikt Erofeev. A premonition of dyingin Stryy causes the protagonist to leave one of these locations in a (+) Heinrich Bo \u0308llnovella titled for punctuality. This setting sees a man named Meir kill his father for bread thrown by local workmen since he had only snow to eat. While in one of these objects, the hysterical (*) Madame Schachter screams about a fire, and after disembarking, the narrator's sister Tzipora is seen for the last time after being told \"Men to the left, women to the right\". For ten points, name this mode of transport that takes Elie Wiesel to Buchenwald with 100 people in his wagon.", "answer": "train", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One ode to this figure states that \"I walked on the grass, on the firm dew thatwas\" this figure. Another ode calls this figure a \"lover of bodies beneath rough cloth\",declares that \"the sun sings in the navels/ of boys who play under bridges\", anddecries (+) \"urban faggots, tumescent flesh and unclean thoughts.\" In another poem,this figure is asked \"Will we walk all night through solitary streets\" and \"Which way does your (*) beard point tonight\". This subject of odes by Pablo Neruda and Federico Garcia Lorca asked \"Who killed the pork chops? What price bananas?\" while \"eyeing the grocery boys\". For ten points, name this poet who was \"poking among the meats in the refrigerator\" in Allen Ginsberg's A Supermarket in California.", "answer": "Walt Whitman", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One character in this novel journals that queueing at a box office but not takinga seat is one way to prevent wasting time. Another character in this novel wakes up at4 a.m. to think of Paris because that is \"the hour his lover is most surely his\". (+) Anasthma patient keeps time by moving peas between two pans, and another character continually tries to perfect a sentence. Dr. (*) Castel's serum proves ineffective, and the doorman M. Michel is the first to die. This novel focuses on the lives of Jean Tarrou, Joseph Grand, and Raymond Rambert during a quarantine. For ten points, name this novel narrated by Bernard Rieux during the title malady written by Albert Camus.", "answer": "The Plague (or La Peste)", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A passerby is amused to hear this character mutter \"puppy biscuit\" to himself.Dr. Pritchard-Mitford tells this character \"I've read your book on streptohricosis\"before treating millionaire banker Wellington McMillan. This character repeatedlyhears the sound (+) \"pocketa-pocketa-pocketa\". This character plans to wear a slingon his arm when taking his car to the garage, and mention of the Waterbury trial precedes this character revealing to a (*) courtroom that he is also a deadly shot with his left hand. This character is scolded by his wife when she finds him sitting in a hotel chair holding his new overshoes after her appointment at the hairdresser. For ten points, name this daydreamer introduced in a James Thurber story about his \"Secret Life\".", "answer": "Walter Mitty", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In one work, this man became indignant over the sexual harassment of his friendby the Zipper King. In another work, he criticized an essay by Frank Conroy subtitledAll This and a Tan, Too. This thinker described a Mary-Tyler-Moore-themed episodeof St. Elsewhere as (+) \"in-joke within in-joke\" in positing that TV culture is one ofirony and ridicule. In Derivative Sport in Tornado Alley, he told of his being blown into a fence during a tennis match in Champaign, Illinois. This author of (*) E Unibus Pluram wrote of a week spent eating at the Five Star Caravelle Restaurant aboard the Nadir in a heavily-footnoted essay. For ten points, name this author who wrote for Harper's Magazine about a trip to the Illinois State Fair and described a Caribbean cruise in A Supposedly Fun Thing I'll Never Do Again.", "answer": "David Foster Wallace", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In this poem, a cloud lines up between the moon and a woman while her husbandmakes a discovery. One character in this poem wants to teach finding water with a\"hazel prong\" to Harold Wilson, who went to college instead. During a debate, onecharacter mentions a (+) brother 13 miles down the road who is a bank director afterthe other defines \"home\" as \"the place where, when you have to go there/ They have to take you in\". The request \"Be kind\" is met with the response (*) \"When was I ever anything but kind to him?\" about a man who had left during the last haying. This poem is structured as a conversation on a porch between a married couple, Mary and Warren, that begins with \"Silas is back\". For ten points, name this poem about the return of an old day laborer by Robert Frost.", "answer": "The Death of the Hired Man", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The end of one play about this protagonist concludes of suffering, forgiveness,defiance, and love that \"This is alone Life, Joy, Empire, and Victory.\" This character'smother describes Zoroaster as \"my dead child\" who \"met his own image walkingin the garden\". He lists (+) medicine, prophecy, and agriculture in a catalog of thearts he had taught. One of his companions describes to her sister Ione the sound of whirlwinds and earthquakes coming from the realm of (*) Demogorgon. This lover of Asia tells of the birth of Epaphus when Io asks when her suffering will end, but he refuses to tell Hermes who will overthrow Zeus, in which he is joined by a chorus of Oceanids. For ten points, name this title character of a closet drama by Percy Shelley and a play by Aeschylus in which he is bound to a rock for giving man fire.", "answer": "Prometheus", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A maid in this play rescinds her two weeks notice after seeing a singinganniversary telegram. One character in this play wins the title Miss Atlantic City 1942and is referred to as Miss Somerset when she (+) breaks character. This play's firstact ends with the request \"Pass up your chairs, everybody. Save the human race.\" Three Muses, Judge Moses, and Homer (*) appear as refugees. Henry had been named Cain and George both develops the alphabet and invents the wheel. The central family of this play has pet dinosaur and a mammoth and survives an ice age. For ten points, name this play about the Antrobus family written by Thornton Wilder.", "answer": "The Skin of Our Teeth", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In this novel, newspapers reported on two-thousand-year-old lotus seedssprouting. The granddaughter of this novel's protagonist is so upset that she doesnot own a kimono that she attacks a dancing girl and is nearly hit by a car. Theprotagonist's daughter-in-law is scarred from (+) forceps used when she was born.The protagonist learns from the newspaper that his son-in-law, Aihara, attempted suicide, and his daughter Fusako moves in with him. The secretary Eiko takes the protagonist to his son's mistress's house; that mistress, (*) Kinuko, is pregnant and funds an abortion for the wife, Kikuko, of her lover, Shuichi. At the beginning of this novel, the protagonist is reminded of death by the title phenomenon. For ten points, identify this novel about the family of Yasuko and the patriarch Ogata Shingo written by Yasunari Kawabata.", "answer": "The Sound of the Mountain (or Yama no Oto)", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The narrator of this work relays the message \"He has gone South for theweek\" to the red man at Marwar Junction, and works as a correspondent for theBackwoodsman. One character in this short story is executed by standing on arope bridge while it is cut down, and another man is recognized after surviving (+)crucifixion by his inch-thick unibrow. Two characters start a lodge of the Freemasons in the Temple of Imbra after gaining a following defending an outnumbered group of archers with their (*) Martini-Henry rifles. Despite the warnings of Billy Fish, one man insists on forcibly taking an Afghan bride, and he loses power when she responds by biting his nose. For ten points, name this short story in which Daniel Dravot and Peachey Carnehan decide to be rulers of Kafiristan written by Rudyard Kipling.", "answer": "The Man Who Would Be King", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The protagonist of this play is told to only put an even number of salt grainson his eggs and that it is illegal for him to will money to his wife in Paris. This playends with an interlude in which a group of doctors confer a degree in pseudo-Latin,and earlier, a character (+) stages a performance about a shepherd Tircis and his lovePhyllis, who is engaged to a rival. An impostor tells one character that the source of all his (*) symptoms is his lungs and suggests removing an arm and an eye after Mr. Purgon dropped him as a client, straining his relationship with Thomas Diafoirus. The protagonist fakes his death to learn that his wife, B \u0301eline, does not care for him but his daughter Angelique and her love Clea \u0301nte do. For ten points, name this play about the hypochondriac Argan written by Mol \u0301\u0131ere.", "answer": "The Imaginary Invalid (or Le Malade Imaginaire or The Hypochondriac)", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A poet in this novel hides as a eunuch at a brothel called The Curtain, whosetwelve prostitutes ceremonially marry him. Another character in this novel has apremonition about a baby-carrying woman with a Canadian accent who turns outto be Tavleen; that character is later told \"Born again, (+) Spoono\". One of theprotagonists saves the other from a fire at the Shaandaar Cafe, and Mishal's breast cancer inspires a hajj into the Arabian Sea led by the (*) butterfly-eating Ayesha. One character kills the mountain climber Alleluia Cone before his suicide. The protagonists spend 111 days on an airstrip in Jalilia, the city of Mahound, when their plane from India is hijacked. For ten points, name this novel in which Saladin Chamcha and Gibreel Farishta survive an airplane explosion written by Salman Rushdie.", "answer": "The Satanic Verses", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature"}], "bonuses": []}